Andrew Westling



hi@andrewwestling.com



linkedin.com/in/andrewwestling



https://andrewwestling.com/resume

Summary

I'm a designer-turned-engineer. I was going to be an architect, but then I got distracted by the web. For the last 9 years, I've been working as a front end engineer.

These days, I build web apps. My favorite things to work on are design systems, and front end features for TypeScript and JavaScript applications. I'm handy with React, Next. is, and Tailwind, among many other tools. I also like to think about how processes scale, and how teams can work together more harmoniously.

Experience



Senior Software Engineer

Forte

Jul 2022 - Mar 2023 (9 months)

First engineering hire. Feature development, setting up tools and culture. Forte is a purpose-built music education platform for teachers and students.

- From scratch: I set up Forte's Next.js application from scratch; I chose tools and workflows to set us up for quick iteration; established a component library to keep things consistent
- Built features: I built the first iteration of various customer-facing features for Forte's marketplace: Teacher Profiles; Certified Institutions; Invitations and Sign Up; Teacher Ratings and Reviews; "Switch Role" functionality; etc.
- UX/Product Architecture: I got to inform the UX, product flow, and overall architecture of a multi-role marketplace application
- Migration: We migrated to Next.js from a prior AWS Amplify application

Tools we used: React, TypeScript, Next.js, GraphQL, Prisma, Tailwind, Flowbite, Ladle, Vercel

Senior Front End Engineer

Monograph

Apr 2021 - Jun 2022 (1 year 3 months)

Design system and feature development for Monograph's applications. Monograph makes tools to help architecture firms manage their projects, budgets, and tasks.

- Design systems: I built components for Monograph's component library; also wrote documentation and set up workflows between Figma and the codebase
- Features: I built assorted customer-facing features: Team Directory; filter functionality for Monograph Resource; Settings UI; etc.
- "Glue" work: A lot of hard-to-quantify things like process documentation, choosing tools, configuration, code reviews, data migration scripts, customer support collaboration, bug triaging, etc.

Tools we used: React, TypeScript, Stitches, Figma, Storybook, GraphQL, Rails, Vercel, Heroku, Linear



Software Engineer

Better

Jul 2018 - Apr 2021 (2 years 10 months)

Design system and feature development for Better's loan origination platform. Better.com is a mortgage lender.

- Design systems: I was one of the first members of Better's Design Systems team; we built libraries to empower our engineering teams to build consistent and clean UIs
- Features: I built assorted borrower-facing features: redisclosure service; "required assets and buffer" logic; authentication/session expiration; UX for uploading a competitor's loan estimate; loan overview page; etc.
- Integrations: I worked on integrations with sales and marketing tools (call scheduling, A/B testing, etc.)

Tools we used: React, TypeScript, Theme UI, Storybook, Ember, Node.js, SCSS, Optimizely, Segment

∆ Software Engineer

Architizer

Sep 2015 - Jun 2018 (2 years 10 months)

Full-stack and front end feature development and infrastructure maintenance for Architizer's platform to help architects find building products.

- Component libraries: I established and maintained a UI component system to speed up feature development, and improve collaboration with designers
- Features: I built internal- and external-facing features: a private messaging interface; directory interfaces to Solr search indexes; etc.
- Integrations: Extended integrations with external tools for analytics, error logging, marketing, and customer support
- Infrastructure: Optimized frontend infrastructure to speed up deployment and improve test coverage
- Tech debt: Pruned AWS resources to reduce costs, and refactored stale application code

Tools we used: React, Next.js, Storybook, styled-components, AngularJS, SCSS, Django, Solr, Segment, Node.js, CircleCl, AWS, Docker, gulp



Software Engineer

EyeCue Lab

Oct 2014 - Aug 2015 (11 months)

Internship-to-hire. Consultancy/agency setting. Built marketing pages and full-stack features for web applications and client projects.

AppleCare Advisor

Apple

Jun 2013 - May 2014 (1 year)

Technical phone support and customer service for macOS products while I completed my degree.

Education

University of Oregon

Bachelor of Architecture (B.Arch.), Architecture 2009 - 2014

E Epicodus

Jul 2014 - Nov 2014